League of Women Voters, Schenectady County Records apap210
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1930-2005; 2.5 cubic ft.
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Women and the Law; Correspondence, Notes, Project Development, 1987-1997 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Women and the Law; Domestic Violence, 1977-1987 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Women and the Law; Newspaper Clippings, 1981-1986 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Women and the Law: Women's Issues Network of Schenectady, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 80)
- Local Program Studies, 1967-2001; 0.5 cubic ft.
  The Local Program Studies series contains information about health care in the Schenectady area. Contents contain information on the Glenridge Hospital, as well as studies done to improve health care.
  - Glenridge Hospital Conversion: Correspondance, 1967; 1975; 1978; 1982-1984; 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Glenridge Hospital Conversion: Meeting Notes, Studies, Strategy, 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Glenridge Hospital Conversion: Newspaper Clippings, 1975-1976; 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Glenridge Hospital Conversion: Publicity and Press Releases, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Healthcare: Adult Services, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Healthcare: County and Community Health Care, Newspaper Clippings, 1990-1992; 1994; 2001; 2003 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Healthcare: County Health Department (1 of 2), 1976-1995; Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Healthcare: County Health Department (2 of 2), 1976-1995; Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Healthcare: County Health Department - Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Healthcare: County of Schenectady Community Health Assessment, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Healthcare: County of Schenectady Proposed Public Health Service System, 1990-06-20 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Healthcare: Consensus, Newspaper Clippings, 1983-1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Healthcare: Consensus, Notes, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Healthcare: Consensus - State Board Reports, 1983-1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Healthcare: Consensus, Study Reports - Publications, 1983-1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Healthcare: Health Insurance, The Uninsured, 1991-1992; 1999 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Healthcare: HMDs, Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Healthcare: Local Government Health Study, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Healthcare: LWV Position Papers, 1993-1998 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Healthcare: Meat Sanitary Code; Proposal for County Health Unit, 1934-1955 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Healthcare: Meat Sanitary Code; Struggle for County Health Unit, 1935-1937 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Healthcare: "Public Dialogue on Healthcare: The Future of Medicare", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Healthcare: Reform-Clinton Plan and NYS - Cuomo's Health Care Advisory Board, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Healthcare: Schenectady Community Survey - Health, Welfare, Recreational Services, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Healthcare: Schenectady County Health Assessment - Phases I and II, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Healthcare: Sexually Transmitted Diseases, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Healthcare: Study, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Healthcare: Study, Phase I, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Healthcare: Study Phase II, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Healthcare: Study Phase II, Consensus Question, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Schenectady City and County Government, 1935-2005; 1 cubic ft.
  The Schenectady City and County Government collection contains information on the city of Schenectady, N.Y. The collection also features information on the criminal justice system.
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - City Charter, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - City Charter Revision, Informational Meetings and Publicty, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - City Charter Revision - Newspaper Clippings, 1967-2001 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - City Charter Revision - Panel Discussion Sponsored by Schenectady County League of Women Voters, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - City Charter Revision - Proposal, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - City Manager Controversy, 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - City Manager Controversy Clippings, 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - Code of the City of Schenectady, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - City of Schenectady, N.Y. - Drive to Return Schenectady to City Manager Form of Government, 1995-2002 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Consolidation: County Reorganization Legislation, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Consolidation: County Reorganization Legislation, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Consolidation: "Interim Report of the Governor's Blue Ribbon Commission on Consolidation of Local Governments", 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Consolidation: Newspaper Clippings, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Consolidation: Newspaper Clippings, 1995-2005 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Consolidation: Productivity, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Consolidation: Schenectady County Government, 1955-1963 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Consolidation: Schenectady County Government, 1970-1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Consolidation: Schenectady County Government, 1980; 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Consolidation: Schenectady County Government, 1990; 1999 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Consolidation: Schenectady County Government, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - County Charter/City Charter, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - County Charter Revison Citizen's Committee Freedom of Information Packet and Request (Schenectady), 2001 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - County Charter Revision Citizen's Committee Member Handbook (Schenectady), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - County Charter Revision Citizens Committee: Organizational Records (Schenectady), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - County Charter Revision Citizen's Committee: Proposal, Farley, Robert T., Legislator, District 3 (Schenectady), 1997-2001 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - County Charter Revision, LVW Reports & Statements, 1961-1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - County: "Know Your County" Project, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - County Legislation, Attack Against County Manager/County Charter, 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - County Legislature, Newspaper Clippings, 1994; 2000 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - County Manager Search, 1965-1973 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - County Manager Search, 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - County Manager Search - Newspaper Clippings, 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - County Manager Search - Qualification and Selection, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - County Management (Schenectady County), 1963; 2000 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Criminal Justice System: City of Schenectady Study, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Criminal Justice System: Schenectady County Court Report, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Criminal Justice System: Schenectady County Jail, 1979-2001 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Criminal Justice System: Schenectady County Jail, Newspaper Clippings, 1976-2004 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Criminal Justice System: Schenectady County Jail Study, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Criminal Justice System: Balancing Justice in New York State, Schenectady County LWV Pilot Project, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - FOCUS (Future Opportunities Created by A Unified Schenectady) - Newspaper Clippings, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - FOCUS - Urban Development Corporation (Downtown Schenectady Redevelopment), 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Proportional Representation Voting with the Council - Manager Plan for Schenectady, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Schenectady County Administrative Code, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Schenectady County Statistics Trends, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Publications, 1925-2004; 1.5 cubic ft.
  The Publications series contains bulletins posted by the League of Women Voters. The series features a variety of publications by the League of Women Voters including publications on voting, being an active citizen, and women's rights in New York.
  - 75 Years of a Great Idea 1920-1955 (VHS Tape), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Action In Albany, 1985; 1988; 1990; 1996 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Annual Report: A Calendar of League Services, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - The Art of Budget Building, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - The Art of Spending Money For a Stronger Leauge; A Better Community, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - The Assembly, State of New York: Task Force on Women's Issues, Summary of Legislation, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - An Assignment from Society: LWV 50th Anniversary Campaign, ca. 1967 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Bulletin, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Bulletin, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Bulletin, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Bulletin, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Bulletin, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Bulletin, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Bulletin, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Bulletin, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Bulletin, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Bulletin, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Bulletin, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Bulletin, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Bulletin, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Bulletin, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Bulletin, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Bulletin, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Bulletin, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Bulletin, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Bulletin, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Bulletin, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Bulletin, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Bulletin, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Bulletin, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Bulletin, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Bulletin, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Bulletin, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Bulletin, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Bulletin, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Bulletin, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Bulletin, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Bulletin, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Bulletin, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Bulletin, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Bulletin, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Bulletin, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Bulletin, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Bulletin, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bulletin, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bulletin, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bulletin, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bulletin, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bulletin, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bulletin, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bulletin, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bulletin, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Bulletin, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Bulletin, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Bulletin, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Bulletin, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Bulletin, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Bulletin, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Bulletin, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Bulletin, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Bulletin, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Bulletin, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - By the People…The Indirect Initiative, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Bylaws of the Leauge of Women Voters of the United States, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Bylaws of the Leauge of Women Voters of New York State, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Capital District Citizens for ACCESS Presents: The Voter's Guide on Reproductive Issues, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Child Abuse and Maltreatment: A Guide for Mandated Reporters, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Citzen Information Service, Undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Citizen Lobbyist: A Guide to Action in Albany, ca. 1976 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Crisis: The Condition of the American City, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Current Focus, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Directory of New York State Officers and Officials (1991-1992) (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Divorce and Seperation in New York State, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Do You Know The ABC's of Your Town's Government?, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Education Fund: Guideline for State and Local League, Use of Tax Deductible Money, Undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Energy, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Equilibrium: The Energy Issue, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Facts and Issues, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Facts for Voters, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - For the New…and Not So New Board Members, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - The Health Care Puzzle in New York State, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - How to Build a Sight and Sound Image, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Impact on Issues in New York State: A Guide to the State League Program (1979-1981), ca. 1980 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Impact on Issues in New York State: State League Program and Action (1981-1983) (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Impact on Issues in New York State: Program and Action of the LWV of New York State (1983-1985) (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Impact on Issues in New York State (1991-1993), 1992 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Intermunicipal Cooperation and Consolidation, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - In League; Guidelines for League Boards, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - It Made A Difference (1919-1969) (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - The Judicial System in New York State, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Legislative Practice and Procedures, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - League of Women Voters of Schenectady, History (1925-1960), ca. 1962 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - League of Women Voters Looks at Schenectady Community College, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - League of Women Voters Looks at Schenectady County Public Welfare, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Life: A Report on the Citizen's View of 1952 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - List of Candidates and Issues Prepared by LWV for GE Constructive Citizens Council, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - "Make a Difference", Undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Making Government Work; Intergovernmental Cooperation, Parterning and Consolidation in New York State, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Making Land Use Decisions in New York State, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - New York State Legislature, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - The New York State Voter, 1981; 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - New York State Women: Newsletter from New York State Division for Women, 1981; 1984 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Presenting Schenectady County Leauge of Women Voters (1975-1976) (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Publications, Etc., 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - The QWL Observer, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Report of the Democratic Task Force on Legislative Ethics, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - The Road to Change: A Local Program Handbook, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Schenectady County Governmental & Political Who's Who, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Schenectady County; A Citizen's Guide to Local Government, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Schenectady LWV Membership Drive Pamphlet, ca. 1967 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Schenectady LWV Membership Drive Pamphlet, 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Simplified Parliamentary Procedure, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Student Conference Pamphlets (Union College), 1945; 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Supercity/ Hometown, U.S.A. Prospects for Two -Tier Government, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - A Survey of Local Government Service & Structures in Schenectady County, New York, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - The National Voter, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - This is Your LWV of Schenectady, 1925-1957, ca. 1961 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - United Nations Decade for Women (1976-1985), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - The Voter, Guide to Candidates and Issues, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Voters Guide,Vol. 1, No. 2, 1941 November (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - What Ever Happened to Open Housing? A Handbook for Fair Housing Monitors, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Women and the Law; A Look at Some of the Laws that Affect Women in New York State, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Women and the Law In New York State, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Women's Guide to Marriage and Divorce in New York, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Woman's Legal Rights in Marriage, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Women's Rights in New York, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Women's Rights in New York State, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Women Workers & Job Health Hazards, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - You are Entering Schenectady County, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - You are Entering Schenectady County, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - You are Entering Schenectady County, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 92)
- Scrapbooks, 1933-1990; 3.4 cubic ft.
  Arranged chronologically
  The Scrapbook series contains newspaper articles and photographs of the League of Women Voters.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1933-1945 (Oversized 1)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1935-1939; 1941 (Oversized 1)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1936 (Oversized 1)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1940-1941 (Oversized 2)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1942-1943 (Oversized 2)
  - Scrapbook 6, 1950 (Oversized 3)
  - Scrapbook 7, 1951-1953 (Oversized 3)
  - Scrapbook 8, 1955-1959 (Oversized 4)
  - Scrapbook 9, 1959-1962 (Oversized 4)
  - Scrapbook 10, 1962-1964 (Oversized 5)
  - Scrapbook 11, 1964-1965 (Oversized 5)
  - Scrapbook 12, 1965-1968 (Oversized 6)
  - Scrapbook 13, 1969-1972 (Oversized 7)
  - Scrapbook 14, 1972-1973 (Oversized 7)
  - Scrapbook 15, 1973-1974 (Oversized 8)
  - Scrapbook 16, 1974-1976 (Oversized 8)
  - Scrapbook 17, 1978 (Oversized 8)
  - Scrapbook 18, 1990 (Oversized 9)
  - Scrapbook 19, Undated (Oversized 9)